Hey, in this lesson, we'll work with unit test.
So unit tests will help us to make sure that our application still works after any changes.
They check some small parts of the app automatically, so we don't have the test everything by hand.
And we shouldn't care if you broke something, we will see it immediately.
In this lesson, we'll ask our source AI to create a plan for covering our app by unit tests.
And it should list what test we need for each file.
So then we'll work to sort generate this test in our codebase regarding to the plan.
We will review it, we will fix and make changes if it's needed.
Then we can run the test and to be sure that all of them correct and works.
And this way, our application will stay stable and easy to update in the future.
So our plan shouldn't include everything we need.
Test in the conversion logic, test in the different components we have right here.
Test in API calls and test in the utils.
And of course, the main application state also works.
So this help us catch problems early and keep our project stable as it told you.
Okay, I prepared a prompt, a pressure prompt, which we'll ask to sort generate all the files,
but we will use the planning mode to first see what crossroads going to cover and might be
adjusted.
So if we need more coverage.
Okay, the prompt is the following.
Create a step-by-step plan to add a run unit test in this application using the test.
With test, it's a util, something like just, but it's a bit newer.
So, and we also ask our all functionality and API requests also more network calls.
Okay, let's ask to sort generate the plan.
And we will see in a minute, oh, what is going to cover.
Okay, first, we need to add a bit test library to the project.
Also, we will use test and library react, library for finding components in a domain, etc.
So, as then we will configure a bit test, of course, it's also needed.
And then the unit test structure will be, so I don't like this test structure, so we will update it.
I don't want to have a separate folder for all tests.
I'd like all the tests, you'll be keep together with the components, just with the test extensions,
for example.
So, let's adjust it, so I can ask it, I'd like to have, let's gather this component.
I said it's clear, so, and you need to adjust the plan.
I, of course, can edit it here, so, but I decided to adjust to our console, rewrite it.
So, use a test.ts.ts.ts.ts file next to source file, not as folder, okay, it's fine.
Then, we will write test for utilities, okay, he's going to cover two utilities, that's fine.
Write test for 8-day models for fetch currencies and get rates.
It's also fine, he will use, he will mock the fetch and network calls.
He will write test for the components, we have a mount input, currency survey, result, and swap
button. He will verify rendering, probes, and main behavior, it's fine, he will also add some
high level tests for application component logic. And he will run and verify all the task works.
So, this is an implementation to do, and with test, test, it deals this IP test components,
this app, and test, so it looks fine. Amazing, I would say, and it will click build.
Oh, of course, I was trying to run all the, he felt installing all the libraries.
Be aware that sometimes you need to approve, you allow to run the command,
course order suggestion. So, we can see that it's adding a new libraries, the test library,
the, with test, he's adding the libraries. And now, he's starting configuring the with test.
And don't like releases configuration, so it's really easy that he, I can help with this,
because you're spending a lot of time on this documentation, trying to configure between
different versions, especially if you use TypeScript. So, it's really fun activity,
but I prefer to delegate it to AI. So, we have first tests for the utils, we have convert
amount.test, and with a test, it tells it to the tune of the right and total, then it's through
an error, if right is not number, and it also handles negative amounts. Okay, looks, okay, I don't
know what has the negative amounts, I guess we not allow it, but okay. Make for the currency,
right, test the different euros, the different symbols. I will also show you a small life hack,
then how we can, for example, optimize this test. So, it makes sense if you have bigger tests,
we can use test dot each, or it ID dot each, so we will just enter in mention all the
values and names for the test, and then it will check, it will implement it on the ones.
But, for this case, we have, we check different, so we have to be, which it's to be the
emojent, we check it to be on the finer, so it doesn't really make sense. So, let's check the rest of the test,
we have amount input, we still see a rose because it's working on it. So, we have the trenders and
input help text, it goes on change, allows only one decimal point, blocking put if you didn't
max integer digits, okay, what it should be, yeah, so we can provide maximum digits.
currency select, it also, we always can optimize it, we can create helpers to render components,
if we like, but I will leave it up to you, you can always optimize your tests.
The result, this was the promoted convention, conversion, yeah, it's fine, the swap button,
we check that it's, render the button and then click off the works, it's for currencies.
We have the get rates API, it fetches, and it mugs the API, and it's tried to get it and
see that we get what we mocked previously, and also check it through an error. For the fetch
currencies, it's the same, it just did one more, can check the smoke is a return it, and also is it
we reacted, it's a bad response, and now we have the application dot test, so we what we test,
we test the application render and can convert, we can enter amount, we can handle swap,
we can show it, or if API fails, so this is a basic test, you of course can extend it at much more
test cases cover some edge cases, but it seems for us, it will be fine, to stop at this point,
I will pick people, okay, now time to test our test works, I will stop the server,
and then we will run, come on, and we are on test, let's see the result, oh, we see, oh, our test
was passed, okay, it's fine, oh, we have, we have, so just seven tests, all of them passed, and we
covered eight files, so this fine, just a quick remark, if your test for some reason doesn't work,
can you have, I don't know, any error in terminal, you can just put it by this error, like
this text, you can just paste it here, and ask, fix this test, and you can do more iterations,
and if you are on paid plan, I recommend for you to use one of the sonnet model, it's much smarter
than the auto model for three points, and you might have the better results, so I think this
everything I'd like to show you, and see you in the next lesson,